Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an upper intermediate level lesson about something
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节中高级课程，内容是关于
very technical.
非常技术性的东西。
We're talking about marketing strategies here today.
我们今天要讨论营销策略。
That's right.
没错。
Today we have an upper intermediate lesson at the office.
今天我们有一节办公室场景的中高级课程。
That is the category of this lesson and we're basically talking about marketing, a marketing
这是这节课的类别，我们主要讨论营销、营销
plan and a lot of technical words around this part of business.
计划以及许多围绕这个商业领域的专业词汇。
All right, so let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in just a moment
好的，那么让我们先听一下今天的对话，稍后我们会回来
to talk about what's going on.
讨论其中的内容。
Okay, everyone, let's begin.
好了，各位，我们开始吧。
I called you here today to evaluate our marketing strategy during this recession.
我今天叫你们来是为了评估我们在经济衰退期间的营销策略。
I wanted to reemphasize our corporate mission of aiming to give our customers the best coffee
我想重申我们的企业使命，即致力于为顾客提供最好的咖啡
and service in a clean and welcoming atmosphere.
和服务，营造一个干净、温馨的氛围。
Several other shops have been reducing their prices for their coffees and they are drawing
其他几家店一直在降低咖啡价格，他们吸引了
in more customers.
更多的顾客。
Why aren't we doing the same thing?
我们为什么不也这么做呢？
I know that recent sales have been slow, but we are not going to reduce our prices to the
我知道最近的销售一直很缓慢，但我们不会把价格降到
level of our competitors.
竞争对手的水平。
We offer a superior product and our focus is on long-term growth rather than short-term
我们提供优质的产品，我们的重点是长期增长，而不是短期
sales.
销售。
If we lower our prices, we run the risk of devaluing our product.
如果我们降价，就有贬低我们产品的风险。
Customers don't care about coffee anymore.
顾客们不再关心咖啡了。
They only care about price.
他们只关心价格。
I disagree.
我不同意。
Highly discerning customers know that our coffee is far better than the coffee you buy
眼光敏锐的顾客知道我们的咖啡远比你在
at the other places.
其他地方买到的要好。
Our coffee beans are artisan roasted and we use state-of-the-art equipment to brew our
我们的咖啡豆是手工烘焙的，我们使用最先进的设备来冲泡
coffees.
咖啡。
When you compare the coffees side by side, our coffee wins the taste test every time.
当你把咖啡放在一起比较时，我们的咖啡每次都能在口味测试中胜出。
We have never sought to appeal to the mass market with cheap coffee drinks and we will
我们从未试图用廉价的咖啡饮品来吸引大众市场，现在
not do so now.
也不会这么做。
That's true.
没错。
We've certainly achieved top-of-mind awareness when it comes to the best tasting brews and
在最佳口味咖啡方面，我们确实已经实现了高知名度，
it's important to distinguish ourselves from the competitors.
并且与竞争对手区分开来很重要。
I think the main question is, how can we show our appreciation to our customers?
我认为主要问题是，我们如何向顾客表达我们的感激之情？
That's the main question I would like to discuss today.
这就是我今天想讨论的主要问题。
Money is tight for everyone these days.
现在大家手头都很紧。
So even our most loyal customers may be reconsidering the money they pay for their morning coffee.
所以即使是我们最忠实的顾客也可能在重新考虑他们为早晨咖啡所花的钱。
Since the security of our coffee beans is one of our core competencies, why don't we
既然咖啡豆的安全性是我们核心竞争力之一，我们为什么不
sell the beans for people to brew coffee at home?
卖咖啡豆让人们在家冲泡咖啡呢？
That could definitely be a way we could expand our company, but would we be undermining the
这绝对是我们扩展公司的一种方式，但那样会不会损害
essence of the company that way?
公司的本质呢？
Let's brainstorm some more ideas and do some research.
让我们集思广益，再想一些点子，并做一些研究。
The customer always comes first and what the customer wants, the customer gets.
顾客永远第一，顾客想要什么，顾客就能得到什么。
Maybe it's time we started selling coffee beans.
也许是时候开始卖咖啡豆了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very interesting dialogue.
一段非常有趣的对话。
I think this is something very common that would go on in a meeting room when the marketing
我认为这是会议室里很常见的情况，当营销
department is talking about prices and how do we increase sales, etc.
部门在讨论价格以及如何增加销售额等等。
So I think we had a lot of difficult words or maybe words that we didn't really understand
所以我认为我们遇到了很多难词，或者可能我们不太理解
well.
的词。
So let's take a look at some of those in Language Takeaway.
那么让我们在“语言要点”环节中看看其中的一些。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first word on the top of our list today is recession.
今天我们列表上的第一个词是“recession”。
Anyone looking at the news this year or last year probably knows what this word means,
任何关注今年或去年新闻的人可能都知道这个词的意思，
but let's talk about it anyway.
但我们还是来讨论一下吧。
What is a recession?
什么是经济衰退？
That's right.
没错。
So someone was talking about the recession and basically it is a noun.
所以有人提到了经济衰退，基本上它是一个名词。
And it means that people don't have enough money like before and so consequently services
意思是人们不像以前那样有足够的钱，因此服务
are decreased, people aren't buying as much, so there is a lack of commerce going on in
减少，人们购买力下降，所以一个国家、地区或城市等
a country, a region, or a city, etc.
的商业活动缺乏。
So basically in economics you have these different cycles.
所以基本上在经济学中，有这些不同的周期。
It's not like the economy is always the same.
经济并不总是一样的。
And so sometimes when there's not enough money we call it a recession and we can say, hey,
所以有时当钱不够时，我们称之为经济衰退，我们可以说，嘿，
I don't have much money to spend right now, we are in a recession.
我现在没有多少钱可花，我们正处于经济衰退中。
So that's a very common way to use the term.
这是使用这个术语的非常常见的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, it's an economic term and many consequences because of this lack of
所以正如你所说，这是一个经济术语，由于缺乏
jobs.
工作机会，会带来很多后果。
It's just, as you said, a cycle.
就像你说的，只是一个周期。
And so apart from a recession, that's why they are brainstorming to see how they can
所以除了经济衰退，这就是为什么他们在集思广益，看看如何
increase sales despite the recession.
能在经济衰退中增加销售。
They also talked about their customers and that their customers are highly discerning.
他们还谈到了他们的顾客，说他们的顾客眼光非常敏锐。
Alright so this word discerning comes from the verb to discern.
好的，这个词“discerning”来自动词“discern”。
And it's a really important one because it means to be able to tell the difference, to
这是一个非常重要的词，因为它意味着能够分辨出区别，
understand the difference between two different things.
理解两件不同事物之间的差异。
Okay so let's say we have two cups of soda.
好的，假设我们有两杯苏打水。
I'm very good at tasting things so I can discern the difference.
我非常擅长品尝东西，所以能分辨出差异。
I can discern the difference between these two.
我能分辨这两者之间的区别。
I can say one is Coca-Cola and one is Pepsi.
我能说一个是可口可乐，一个是百事可乐。
Okay so to discern is to be able to tell the difference or to notice the difference between
好的，所以“discern”就是能够区分或注意到不同之处，
many things.
在众多事物之间。
And so obviously you are a discerning person.
显然，你是一个有辨别力的人。
Or you have discerning taste.
或者你有挑剔的品味。
This means that you're very good at telling when something is high quality and when it's
这意味着你非常擅长判断某样东西是否高质量，
not high quality.
还是不够高质量。
And well talking about discerning customers who know what they want.
嗯，说到那些知道自己想要什么的挑剔顾客。
And so they talked about their coffee beans and it's one of their core competencies.
所以他们谈到了他们的咖啡豆，这是他们的核心竞争力之一。
Okay so this is something you might actually hear in education as well as in business.
好的，这你在教育领域和商业领域都可能听到。
Something is your competency if you are able to do it.
如果你能做某事，那它就是你的能力。
Alright so I am able to write Chinese characters.
好的，所以我能写汉字。
It's one of my core competencies.
这是我的核心竞争力之一。
Okay so that's something that I'm able to do so I consider it one of these central or
好的，所以这是我能做的事情，因此我认为它是这些核心或
important abilities.
重要的能力之一。
But you always talk about competencies within the context of some area.
但你总是在某个领域的背景下谈论能力。
So my language skills or in this case at a company we're talking about making a coffee.
所以我的语言技能，或者在这个案例中，在一家公司里，我们谈论的是制作咖啡。
One of the company's core competencies is making their coffee beans.
这家公司的核心竞争力之一就是制作他们的咖啡豆。
That's something they're good at.
那是他们擅长的事情。
That's right and core when we talk about core we talk about the center.
没错，而核心，当我们说核心时，指的是中心。
We talk about one of the most important things.
我们说的是最重要的事情之一。
That's right.
没错。
Okay and well for the last word that we've prepared to you on Language Takeaway we talked
好的，那么对于我们在“语言要点”中准备的最后一个词，我们谈到了
about them worrying that you know selling the coffee beans might undermine the essence
他们担心，你知道，卖咖啡豆可能会削弱公司的本质。
of the company.
削弱。
To undermine.
Okay this is a really important verb and you'll hear this a lot actually in TV shows and especially
好的，这是一个非常重要的动词，你会在电视节目里经常听到，尤其是在
in dramas.
剧情片里。
Say he's undermining my authority or he's undermining my power.
比如，他在削弱我的权威，或者他在削弱我的权力。
This means that someone is challenging it or someone is kind of taking it away from
这意味着有人在挑战它，或者有人在某种程度上把它从你身边
you.
夺走。
So to undermine is to as you said challenge or try to take something from you very sneaky
所以，削弱就像你说的，挑战或试图从你那里拿走一些东西，有时是偷偷摸摸地
in a sneaky way sometimes.
以狡猾的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So for example if I'm the president of a country and someone is trying to take that away from
比如，如果我是某个国家的总统，有人试图从我这里夺走这个位置，
me someone is trying to be the president and trying to take down my government.
有人想当总统，试图推翻我的政府。
He is trying to undermine my power.
他就是在试图削弱我的权力。
Okay very good.
好的，非常好。
So four key words there on Language Takeaway.
所以在“语言小贴士”部分有四个关键词。
Now we're going to move on to Fluency Builder where we prepared a lot of nice and very good
现在我们进入“流利度训练”环节，我们准备了很多很棒且非常实用的
phrases.
短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
All right so on Fluency Builder why don't we start up from the beginning of the dialogue
好的，在流利度训练中，我们不妨从对话的开头开始，
when they were talking about the prices of the coffee and that other shops have reduced
当时他们在谈论咖啡的价格，以及其他店铺已经降价，
their prices and so they're drawing in more customers.
从而吸引了更多顾客。
All right so the key here is to draw in.
好的，这里的关键是“吸引”。
This is a phrase.
这是一个短语。
Most people will know the word to draw you know to make a design on a page.
大多数人知道“draw”这个词，意思是“在纸上画画”。
But to draw in has a very special meaning.
但“draw in”有一个非常特殊的含义。
It means to attract.
它的意思是“吸引”。
Okay so you want to attract more customers.
好的，所以你想吸引更多顾客。
You want to bring them into the shop.
你想把他们带进店里。
So you're trying to draw them in.
所以你试图吸引他们进来。
So Marco what's a good example of something that a company will do to try and draw in
那么Marco，公司为了吸引顾客，通常会做什么好的例子呢？
customers.
顾客。
For example many of you maybe have seen in fast food restaurants when they have a promotion
例如，你们很多人可能见过快餐店搞促销，
like you buy one hamburger and you get another one for free.
比如买一个汉堡，再免费送一个。
So that's maybe one of the strategies that they're trying to do to draw in customers
这可能是他们试图吸引顾客的策略之一。
and maybe not make money but give people the opportunity to taste their good food.
也许不赚钱，但让人们有机会品尝他们的好食物。
That's right.
没错。
All right so the next phrase we've got here is a little bit different.
好了，我们接下来的这个短语有点不一样。
It's talking about the kind of product that they have.
它说的是他们产品的类型。
They're talking about their coffee beans and they say that they're roasted and that they
他们在谈论他们的咖啡豆，说这些豆子是经过烘焙的，而且他们
use state of the art equipment to brew the coffee.
使用最先进的设备来冲泡咖啡。
So this phrase state of the art.
所以这个短语是“state of the art”。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Okay if something is state of the art, okay, we're usually talking about a machine and
好的，如果某样东西是“state of the art”，我们通常指的是机器，
we're saying that it's the latest in technology.
意思是它是最新的技术。
It's very very new.
非常非常新。
It's highly advanced.
非常先进。
It's a very technologically advanced machine.
是一台技术非常先进的机器。
So for example the new iPhone 4 is a state of the art cell phone.
比如，新的iPhone 4就是一款最先进的手机。
That means it's the very highest that technology has to offer.
这意味着它是技术所能提供的最高水平。
And obviously something that is state of the art is not state of the art forever because
显然，最先进的东西不会永远是最先进的，因为
technology changes and so maybe next year there will be a new state of the art telephone.
技术会变化，所以也许明年会有新的最先进的手机。
That's right.
没错。
So if you notice the spelling as well we have little hyphens between each word.
如果你注意拼写，每个单词之间都有小连字符。
State of the art because we take it as a chunk all together, right?
“State of the art”是因为我们把它当作一个整体来看，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And following that we have another phrase that is used to talk about products.
接下来，我们还有另一个用来谈论产品的短语。
They say when you compare the coffees we have side by side, our coffee wins against our
他们说，当你把我们两家的咖啡放在一起比较时，我们的咖啡胜过
competitors.
竞争对手。
So side by side.
所以是“并排比较”。
In this case the phrase there is side by side and they're talking about comparing coffees
在这个例子中，短语是“side by side”，他们在谈论并排比较咖啡。
side by side.
并排比较。
So I think this is pretty literal.
所以我觉得这很直白。
It's basically saying you put two coffee mugs or coffee cups together side by side and you
基本上就是说，你把两个咖啡杯并排放在一起，
have people taste and then you see which one they prefer.
让人们品尝，然后看他们更喜欢哪一个。
That's right.
没错。
So you can say this when you're making comparisons.
所以你在做比较时可以用这个说法。
When I look at them side by side I think I like the pink one more than the red one.
当我并排看它们时，我觉得我更喜欢粉色的那个，而不是红色的。
So you are comparing, you are literally putting them next to each other to make a choice of
所以你在比较，你实际上是把它们放在一起，以便做出选择，
which one is your preference.
决定你更喜欢哪一个。
That's right.
没错。
Okay now moving on we have a very interesting phrase when they were talking about the company
好了，接下来我们有一个非常有趣的短语，当他们谈论公司时，
and they've achieved top of mind awareness when it comes to best tasting brews.
他们在最佳口味咖啡方面实现了“首要意识”。
So this phrase top of mind awareness very closely related to marketing.
所以这个短语“top of mind awareness”与市场营销密切相关。
What are we talking about here?
我们在这里讨论什么呢？
Well let's look at the individual words.
让我们看看每个单词。
We have top which is on top not on bottom, mind which is your head or your thinking and
我们有“top”，意思是顶部而不是底部；“mind”，意思是你的头脑或思维；以及
awareness which is the way that you see things.
“awareness”，意思是你看待事物的方式。
And so let's take a guess here and say that when I think of a category of product like
所以让我们猜一下，当我想起一类产品，比如咖啡时，
coffee for example, what is the first thing that comes into my mind?
我脑海中首先浮现的是什么？
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually a very cool game that you can sometimes play with friends.
所以这其实是一个可以和朋友们一起玩的很有趣的游戏。
Basically just say okay when you think of coffee what is the first brand that comes
基本上就是问，当你想到咖啡时，你脑海中第一个出现的品牌是什么？
into your mind?
你脑海中第一个出现的品牌是什么？
Starbucks.
星巴克。
So that for example shows that Starbucks has put in you a certain top of mind awareness.
所以这显示星巴克在你心中建立了某种首要意识。
You associate coffee with Starbucks immediately.
你立刻把咖啡和星巴克联系起来。
You don't say Costa Coffee, you don't say Coffee Bean or any other brand.
你不会说Costa Coffee，也不会说Coffee Bean或其他任何品牌。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah, no definitely this is a way for you to really test what companies, what corporations
是的，这绝对是一种测试哪些公司、哪些企业
have the most effective marketing because obviously they're the ones who make you think
拥有最有效营销的方式，因为显然是他们让你想到了这个东西。
of this thing.
没错。
That's right.
They have lots of marketing campaigns.
他们有很多营销活动。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually very interesting.
所以这其实非常有趣。
So you can say top of mind or you can say top of mind awareness.
所以你可以说“top of mind”或“top of mind awareness”。
You can say Honda has great top of mind among their clients.
你可以说本田在客户中拥有很高的首要意识。
Or Ferrari has great top of mind among luxury vehicles.
或者法拉利在豪华车中拥有很高的首要意识。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And now for the last phrase when we talked about money again, this is a very nice colloquial
现在最后一个短语，我们又谈到了钱，这是一种非常口语化的
way of saying that you don't have a lot of money or money is very scarce right now.
说法，表示你钱不多或现在钱很紧张。
Alright, so the phrase is money is tight.
好的，所以这个短语是“money is tight”。
Alright?
对吧？
So you know the word tight, you can hold something tightly or this belt is tight, I'm gaining
你知道“tight”这个词，你可以紧紧抓住某物，或者这条腰带很紧，我长胖了。
weight.
我长胖了。
But in this case, money is tight, that's a phrase we take as a chunk and it means like
但在这个情况下，“money is tight”是一个固定短语，意思是
you say Marco, I just don't have much money right now.
你说，Marco，我现在没多少钱。
So money is tight right now.
所以现在钱很紧张。
Now it's interesting because you can say it money is tight and then the subject.
有趣的是，你可以说“money is tight”，然后加上主语。
Money is tight for Bill right now.
比尔现在钱很紧张。
Or you can say Bill is tight for money at the moment.
或者你可以说比尔目前手头紧。
So you can switch it up depending on where you put the subject, towards the end or in
所以你可以根据主语放在结尾还是开头来调整语序。
the beginning.
开头。
Alright, so usually you hear the phrase money is tight right now or money is really tight,
好的，所以你通常听到“money is tight right now”或“money is really tight”，
just kind of on its own and it's a way to say I don't have much cash.
单独使用，这是一种表示我没多少钱的方式。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of words and phrases here.
所以我们在这里看了很多单词和短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
Okay everyone, let's begin.
好了，各位，我们开始吧。
I called you here today to evaluate our marketing strategy during this recession.
我今天叫你们来是为了评估我们在经济衰退期间的营销策略。
I wanted to reemphasize our corporate mission of aiming to give our customers the best coffee
我想重申我们的公司使命，即致力于在干净、温馨的环境中为顾客提供最好的咖啡
and service in a clean and welcoming atmosphere.
和服务。
Several other shops have been reducing their prices for their coffees and they are drawing
其他几家店一直在降低咖啡价格，吸引了更多顾客。
in more customers.
吸引了更多顾客。
Why aren't we doing the same thing?
我们为什么不也这么做呢？
I know that recent sales have been slow, but we are not going to reduce our prices to the
我知道最近的销售一直很慢，但我们不会把价格降到
level of our competitors.
竞争对手的水平。
We offer a superior product and our focus is on long-term growth rather than short-term
我们提供优质产品，我们的重点是长期增长，而不是短期
sales.
销售。
If we lower our prices, we run the risk of devaluing our product.
如果我们降价，就有贬低我们产品的风险。
Customers don't care about coffee anymore.
顾客不再关心咖啡了。
They only care about price.
他们只关心价格。
I disagree.
我不同意。
Highly discerning customers know that our coffee is far better than the coffee you buy
眼光敏锐的顾客知道，我们的咖啡比你在其他地方买的咖啡好得多，
at the other places.
在别的地方。
Our coffee beans are artisan roasted and we use state-of-the-art equipment to brew our
我们的咖啡豆是手工烘焙的，我们使用最先进的设备来冲泡我们的
coffees.
咖啡。
When you compare the coffees side by side, our coffee wins the taste test every time.
当你把咖啡放在一起比较时，我们的咖啡每次都能在口味测试中胜出。
We have never sought to appeal to the mass market with cheap coffee drinks and we will
我们从未试图用廉价的咖啡饮品来吸引大众市场，我们也不会
not do so now.
现在也不会这么做。
That's true.
没错。
We've certainly achieved top-of-mind awareness when it comes to the best tasting brews and
在最佳口味咖啡方面，我们确实已经达到了品牌首选认知度，
it's important to distinguish ourselves from the competitors.
与竞争对手区分开来很重要。
I think the main question is, how can we show our appreciation to our customers?
我认为主要问题是，我们如何向顾客表达我们的感激之情？
That's the main question I would like to discuss today.
这是我今天想讨论的主要问题。
Money is tight for everyone these days, so even our most loyal customers may be reconsidering
如今大家手头都紧，即使是我们最忠实的顾客也可能在重新考虑
the money they pay for their morning coffee.
他们为早晨咖啡花的钱。
Since the security of our coffee beans is one of our core competencies, why don't we
既然咖啡豆的供应安全是我们的核心竞争力之一，我们为什么不
sell the beans for people to brew coffee at home?
卖咖啡豆让人们在家冲泡咖啡呢？
That could definitely be a way we could expand our company, but would we be undermining the
这绝对可以成为我们公司扩张的一种方式，但这样会不会削弱
essence of the company that way?
公司的本质？
Let's brainstorm some more ideas and do some research.
让我们再集思广益一些想法，做些研究。
The customer always comes first and what the customer wants, the customer gets.
顾客永远第一，顾客想要什么，顾客就能得到什么。
Maybe it's time we started selling coffee beans.
也许是时候开始卖咖啡豆了。
All right, so going back to top-of-mind awareness, let's test what brands are in your head.
好了，回到品牌首选认知度这个话题，我们来测试一下你脑子里有哪些品牌。
For example, when you think of a luxury sports car, what do you think?
比如，当你想到豪华跑车时，你会想到什么？
Ferrari.
法拉利。
Ferrari, you mentioned it before.
法拉利，你之前提到过。
Or Lamborghini.
或者兰博基尼。
Or Lamborghini, but you said Ferrari first.
或者兰博基尼，但你首先说的是法拉利。
When you think of a brand of cigarettes, what do you think?
当你想到香烟品牌时，你会想到什么？
Camel.
骆驼。
Camel, okay.
骆驼，好的。
This is an American brand.
这是一个美国品牌。
I don't think it's found very commonly in other places.
我觉得在其他地方不太常见。
They have it in Europe.
欧洲有。
It's very popular.
很受欢迎。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
What about when you think of computers, what do you think?
那当你想到电脑时，你会想到什么？
For some reason, IBM.
不知为什么，IBM。
IBM, even though you don't own an IBM.
IBM，尽管你并没有IBM的电脑。
I don't, but I grew up around the IBM revolution.
我没有，但我是在IBM革命时期长大的。
Okay, see, this is interesting.
好的，看，这很有趣。
So actually, it doesn't always work that way, that because you have a brand in your mind,
所以实际上，情况并不总是那样，因为你脑子里有一个品牌，
it doesn't necessarily mean that you will purchase it in the future if you have the
并不一定意味着如果你有能力，你将来就会购买它，
power to, but at least you are aware of the brand and you recognize it, and the chances
但至少你了解这个品牌并认识它，而且你购买它的可能性
are that you will buy it.
很大。
That's right, and you're going to be familiar with it when you read about it or when people
没错，而且当你读到它或别人谈论它时，你会对它感到熟悉。
talk about it.
So for example, I own a Mac computer, Apple, but when I think of computers, I just think
比如，我有一台苹果Mac电脑，但当我想到电脑时，我只会想到
of IBM because we used to say, remember, IBM compatible.
IBM，因为我们以前常说，记得吗，IBM兼容。
Nah, that's right, IBM compatible, because before it was usually just Mac.
不，没错，IBM兼容，因为以前通常只有Mac。
Everything was for Mac.
一切都是为Mac设计的。
Mac or IBM.
Mac或IBM。
And then all of a sudden, it's PC or Mac.
然后突然之间，变成了PC或Mac。
Right.
对。
Actually, that's interesting, though, because if probably, if I say, what do you think of
不过，这其实很有趣，因为如果我说，当你想到
when you think of, what brand comes to mind when you think of MP3 players?
MP3播放器时，你会想到什么品牌？
Apple, the iPod.
苹果，iPod。
You probably think iPod.
你可能会想到iPod。
That's probably one of the most famous ones, but maybe if you ask somebody about 10 years
那可能是最著名的之一，但如果你问别人大约10年前，
ago, when you think about a music player, what do you think about?
当你想到音乐播放器时，你会想到什么？
Sony, the Sony Walkman.
索尼，索尼随身听。
The Sony Walkman, right, or the Sony Discman.
索尼随身听，对，或者索尼CD随身听。
That's right, had both.
没错，我两个都有过。
It was like I had a Walkman, it was bright yellow.
我有个随身听，是亮黄色的。
So this is really interesting.
所以这真的很有趣。
This is the way that you see more or less, you can start to realize what brands are in
这样你或多或少就能开始意识到你脑子里有哪些品牌，
your mind and maybe unconsciously, you may not even be a smoker, but maybe some sort
也许无意识地，你甚至可能不抽烟，但某种
of cigarette brand will be in your mind.
香烟品牌会留在你脑子里。
Or maybe you don't even really like sports cars, but you will have a sports car brand
或者你可能并不真的喜欢跑车，但你脑子里会有个跑车品牌。
in your mind.
I'm very curious to hear what you guys have to say, because obviously, the brands that
我很想听听你们的看法，因为显然，我们意识到的品牌
we're aware of are dependent on where we come from and the marketing campaigns in our home
取决于我们来自哪里、我们本国的营销活动
countries and also our age.
以及我们的年龄。
I was a teenager when I had the Sony Discman, so that made an impact on me.
我十几岁的时候有过索尼CD随身听，所以那对我影响很大。
But let's throw that out to you guys.
但让我们把这个问题抛给你们。
Let us know what you think of when we say luxury cars or MP3 players or computers.
告诉我们，当我们说豪华车、MP3播放器或电脑时，你会想到什么。
Or maybe even basic things like detergents.
或者甚至像洗涤剂这样的基本东西。
For example, if you ask somebody in the United States, they might say Tide.
比如，如果你问一个美国人，他们可能会说“汰渍”。
But if you ask somebody in South America, they might say, I don't know, Omo.
但如果你问一个南美人，他们可能会说，嗯，不知道，“奥妙”。
It's some type of brand.
这是某种品牌。
So, this is also very interesting to see what your local brands have been doing.
所以，看看你们当地的品牌在做什么也很有趣。
That's right.
没错。
So, let us know what you're thinking.
那么，告诉我们你的想法吧。
We're on EnglishPod.com.
我们在EnglishPod.com上。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
Take care.
保重。